Here's the idea of using bootstrapping to
إليكم فكرة استخدام التشغيل التجريبي
simulate the sampling distribution for any statistic.
لمحاكاة توزيع العينات لأية إحصائية.
This might take more than one time through to fully grasp. So bear with me.
قد يستغرق هذا الأمر أكثر من مرة حتى يتم استيعابه بشكل كامل. لذا، أرجو أن تحملوا معي.
We know that in inferential statistics,
نعلم أنه في الإحصاء الاستدلالي،
we want to use a statistic to try and say
نريد استخدام إحصائية لمحاولة قول
something about the corresponding population parameter.
شيء ما عن المعلمة السكانية المقابلة.
Imagine we treat our sample as if it were the entire population.
تخيل أننا نتعامل مع العينة كما لو كانت جميع السكان.
So although these 21 cups represent only a sample of Udacity students,
وعلى الرغم من أن هذه الكؤوس الـ 21 لا تمثل سوى عينة من طلاب جامعة Udacity،
imagine we treat them as though they were in our entire population.
إلا أنه يمكن تخيل أننا نعاملهم كما لو كانوا في جميع سكاننا.
If these 21 individuals are truly representative of our population,
إذا كان هؤلاء الأفراد الـ 21 يمثلون حقًا سكاننا،
we can bootstrap sample from them to understand how
فيمكننا إنشاء عينة منهم لفهم كيف
the proportion of coffee drinkers might change from one sample to the next.
تتغير نسبة من يشربون القهوة من عينة إلى أخرى.
Here, I set up an array of 21 ones and
هنا، سأقوم بإعداد مصفوفة مكونة من 21 واحد
zeroes to represent the cups and the previous image.
وأصفار لتمثيل الأكواب والصورة السابقة.
I also set the seed,
أنا أيضا وضع قيمة البداية،
in case you want to follow along and get the same results.
في حال رغبتكم في المتابعة والحصول على نفس النتائج.
We can calculate the proportion of coffee drinkers in our original sample.
يمكننا حساب نسبة من يشربون القهوة في العينة الأصلية.
Now, let's take our first bootstrap sample of
الآن، دعونا نأخذ أول عينة تمهيدية
the same size as the original sample and calculate the proportion of coffee drinkers.
بنفس حجم العينة الأصلية ونحسب نسبة من يشربون القهوة.
Notice, this proportion doesn't match the original because we're
لاحظوا أن هذه النسبة لا تتطابق مع النسبة الأصلية لأننا
not just sampling the original observations again but rather,
لا نقوم فقط بأخذ عينات من الملاحظات الأصلية مرة أخرى، ولكننا
we're sampling them with replacement.
نقوم بأخذ عينات منها باستبدالها.
We could write a loop to reform
يمكننا كتابة حلقة لإصلاح
the same sampling 10,000 times to see how the proportion will change.
نفس العينة 10000 مرة لنرى كيف ستتغير النسبة.
Finally, let's plot the proportions to look at the sampling distribution.
أخيرا، دعونا نرسم النسب لننظر في توزيع العينات.
Use your sampling distribution results to answer the questions in the next concept.
استخدموا نتائج توزيع العينات الخاصة بكم للإجابة على الأسئلة في المفهوم التالي